Guide to the Katharine Buell Wilder Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Professional Correspondence, 1907-1954; Series II; 0.25; (1 box)
  - "G-H" general, 1917-49, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1940-41 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Hapgood, Norman, 1915-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Hare, James H., 1941-43 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Hurst, Fannie, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - "J" general, 1907-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - "L" general, 1925-44 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1928-29, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - "M" general, 1915-41 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - McCutcheon, John T., 1925, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Mitchel, John Purroy, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - "N" general, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - "P" general, 1922-37 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - "R-S" general, 1916-48, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1914-49 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - "T-Y" general, 1914-41 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Unidentified, 1915-45, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
- Writings, 1908-1941; Series III; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Writings, has been arranged alphabetically by title and subject.
  - "The Chisolm Trail" by John Noble, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 97-98)
  - Early writings
    - The Smith College Monthly, 1908-10 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Collier's, 1912-13 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - "For God and Country: The Life and Military Career of John Wesley Bennett" by Wilder Buell (Box 5, Folder 101-02)
  - "The French King Bridge" by Katharine B. Wilder, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - "French King Valley" by Wilder Buell, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 104-09)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Oversize, Box 13, folder 267
  - "Kipling's Home in America"
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Typescript, ca. 1941 (Box 5, Folder 111-12)
    - "The Kipling That Nobody Read" by Edmund Wilson, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Rudyard Kipling's Vermont Feud by Frederic F. Van De Water, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - "The Last of the Wintersets", [1924?] (Box 6, Folder 115-16)
  - "The Murder of Elliott Speer, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Newspaper article: "Queer Porto Rico" by Robert H. Wilder, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - The Other Side of Main Street
    - Papers, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Reader's report, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Review, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Propaganda and pacifism by K. L. Buell, 1927-28 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Short story: "The English Blessé" by Katharine Buell, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Writing fragments, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 124)
- Family Papers, 1774-1986; Series IV; 1; (3 boxes)
  Family Papers have been alphabetically and then chronologically arranged by person and subject.
  - Announcements and invitations, 1929, 1944, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Buell family: Don Carlos legend
    - Correspondence, 1937-86 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Papers, 1881-1972, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Buell, Alfred Ely, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Buell, Lucy Burton, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Clark family, 1980, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Deming, Theresa Osterheld, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Greeley, Horace: writings, [1869?] (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Hanford family: genealogy, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - Heinz, Bernard, 1880-1968
    - The Heinz Store, 1922, 1957, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Papers, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Summer home on Deer Lake (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Heinz, Bernard, 1915-
    See also: Box 17, folders 296-97
    - Baby book, 1915-20 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Childhood correspondence, 1915-26, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Papers, 1916-29 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Report card, 1924-25 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Heinz, Jeanne Samter
    - Autograph photographs, 1933, 1943, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Guest book, 1914-43, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Wedding, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - World War I memorabilia, 1915-18, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Heinz, Maurice, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Heinz, Susanna Wilder
    See also: Box 17, folders 298-301
    - Address: "Three Elements of Religion", 1949 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Articles about, 1952-73 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Camp Arden: Children's Crusade, 1923, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 149-50)
    - Case of Harriet Lila Swan, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Drawing and poem (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Scrapbooks
      See: Oversize, Box 14, folders 268-69
    - Smith College, 1938-42 (Box 7, Folder 153-54)
    - Writings: "What Women Can Do and Have", 1944 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Holman-Barrett family papers, 1844-1917, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Klauber family
    See also: Oversize, Box 13, folder 270
    - Papers, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - Reminiscences, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - Levy, Louis Samter
    - Biographical information, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - "Yesterdays", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - Loving family
    - Genealogy, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 161)
    - Papers, 1774-1844 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1866-1942, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852: ALS to "My dear Sir" with magazine portrait, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Nast, Thomas
    See: Box 9, folder 190
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Miscellaneous, 1940, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Northfield, Mass., 1929, 1935, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Obituaries, 1935-49, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Wilder-Buell families, 1941-48 (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Noble family, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Printed works
    See also: Oversize, Box 14, folder 271
    - Flood Views: Franklin County and Vicinity, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Miniature almanac by Merriam and Merrill, 1858 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Samter family: genealogy, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 173)
    See also: Box 17, folder 302
  - Samter, Julia Klauber
    - Biographical information, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Notebook of German exercises, 1875-76 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Samter, Samuel
    See also: Oversize, Box 13, folder 272
    - Obituaries, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - Papers, 1922, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Speer, Elliott
    - Memorial service, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 179)
      See also: Oversize, Box 14, folder 273
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur
    - "Kipling and Vermont", 1954 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Papers, 1926-43, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Stoddard, Major F. R., 1918-19 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Wilder & Buell
    See: Box 17, folder 303
  - Wilder family
    - Genealogy, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - Papers, 1822-77 (Box 9, Folder 184)
  - Wilder, George Frederick and Abigail Holman, 1861-1936 (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - Wilder, George Sheldon, 1857, 1873 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Wilder, Harold, 1885 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - Wilder, Herbert Merrill
    See also: Box 17, folder 304
    - Correspondence about, 1971-74 (Box 9, Folder 188)
    - Obituaries, 1915, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 189)
    - Nast, Thomas: ALS to, 1881 Jan 6 (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - Wilder, Katharine Buell
    - Autobiography, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 191)
    - Baby book
      See: Oversize, Box 14, folder 274
    - Biographical information, 1915-57 (Box 9, Folder 192)
    - Campaign broadside, [1930] (Box 9, Folder 193)
    - Papers, 1915, 1926, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 194)
    - Scrapbook
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 275
    - Wedding announcement, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 195)
  - Wilder, Robert Holman
    - Biographical information, 1920-41, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 196)
    - Cartoons and drawings, 1921-46, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 197-99)
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folders 276-79
    - Certificates and diplomas
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 280
    - Children's game, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Graduation exercises, 1900-02 (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - Greeting cards, 1924-27, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 202)
    - Obituaries, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Papers, 1918, 1927, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 204-05)
    - Pension bills, 1930-34 (Box 9, Folder 206)
    - Watercolors
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 281
- Photographs, 1871-1957; Series V; 1; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs are alphabetically arranged.
  - Art Institute, Zürich, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 207)
  - Buell family
    See: Oversize, Box 16, folders 282-84
  - Buell, Anna Dodge, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 208)
  - Buell, Lucy Burton, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 208)
  - Buell, Susanna Loving, [1885?] (Box 10, Folder 209)
  - Buell, Starling Loving, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 210)
  - Columbus, Ohio, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 211)
  - Durkee, Augustus, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 212)
  - Fuchs, Doris Samter Levy, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 213)
  - Heinz and Levy houses, Scranton, Pa., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 214)
  - The Heinz Store, 1925, 1957, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 215-16)
  - Heinz, Bernard, 1880-1968, 1891-1915, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 217-18)
  - Heinz, Bernard, 1915-, 1933, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 219)
    See also: Box 17, folder 305
  - Heinz, Jeanne Samter, 1907-13, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 220-25)
    See also: Oversize, Box 16, folders 285-86
  - Heinz, Susanna Wilder, 1921-66, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 226-29)
    - Family snapshots, 1922-40, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 230-31)
  - Holman family, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - Klauber family, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - Loving family, 1871, 1886, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 234-35)
  - Merrill, Pliny, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 236)
  - Noble, Elizabeth Edmiston Loving Hamilton, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - Northfield, Mass., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - 1938 hurricane (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - Tercentenary portrait, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 240)
  - Postcard, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 241)
  - Samter family, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 242-43)
    See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 287
  - Samter, Bertha Sasser, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 244)
  - Samter, Jacob, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 244)
  - Samter, Julia Klauber, 1908, 1950, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 245-46)
  - Samter, Samuel, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 247)
    See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 288
  - Samter, Samuel and Julia Klauber Samter, 1927, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 248)
  - Wilder family, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 249-50)
    - Hinsdale, N. H. house, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 251)
  - Wilder, Abigail Grace Holman, 1889, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 252)
  - Wilder, George Frederick, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 253-54)
  - Wilder, George Sheldon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 255)
  - Wilder, Herbert Merrill, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 256)
  - Wilder, Katharine Buell, 1891, 1917, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 257-59)
  - Wilder, Robert Holman, 1886-1928, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 260-64)
    See also: Oversize, Box 16, folders 289-90
  - Wilder, Sally Merrill, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - Wilder, Samuel, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - Wilder, Sereno M., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 266)
- Oversize, 1889-1965; 3.25; (4 boxes)
  Oversize papers are alphabetically arranged in series order.
  - WRITINGS
    - "French King Valley"
      - Illustrations by Robert Holman Wilder, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 267)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - Heinz, Susanna Wilder
      - Scrapbook, 1926-42 (Box 13, Folder 268)
      - Scrapbook, 1944-49 (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Klauber family: "Bavaria", 1965 (Box 13, Folder 270)
    - Printed works: Vermont Phoenix, 1835 Mar 13 (Box 13, Folder 271)
    - Samter, Samuel: passport, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - Speer, Elliott: scrapbook about, 1934-37 (Box 14, Folder 273)
    - Wilder, Katharine Buell
      - Baby book, 1889-91 (Box 14, Folder 274)
      - Scrapbook, 1904-08 (Box 15, Folder 275)
    - Wilder, Robert Holman
      - Cartoons, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 276)
      - Cartoons and games, 1915-26 (Box 15, Folder 277-78)
      - Drawings, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 279)
      - Diplomas and certificates, 1905-30 (Box 15, Folder 280)
      - Watercolors, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 281)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Buell family
      - House near Tacoma, Wash., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 282)
      - Darwin, Katharine, and Starling Buell (Box 16, Folder 283)
      - Anna Dodge Buell and grandchildren, Painesville, Ohio (Box 16, Folder 284)
    - Heinz, Jeanne Samter
      - Album, 1906-12 (Box 16, Folder 285)
      - Album, 1913-22 (Box 16, Folder 286)
    - Samter family, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 287)
    - Samter, Samuel, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 288)
    - Wilder, Robert Holman, 1917-18 (Box 16, Folder 289-90)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 18: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folders 19-20 (Box 18, Folder 306)
  - Box 2, folders 25, 27, 29-32 (Box 18, Folder 307-08)
  - Box 4, folders 73, 79, 83, 88 (Box 18, Folder 309)
  - Box 5, folders 98, 103-04, 112 (Box 18, Folder 310-13)
  - Box 6, folder 119 (Box 18, Folder 314)
  - Box 7, folders 126-27, 144 (Box 18, Folder 315-16)
  - Box 9, folders 188, 194 (Box 18, Folder 317-18)
- Additions since 1987, 1764-1996
  - 1987 Addition, 1921-1987; 0.5; (1 box)
    The papers are arranged in series order.
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 291-93)
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 294-95)
    - FAMILY PAPERS
      - Heinz, Bernard, 1915-
        - Mining property, 1963-71 (Box 17, Folder 296-97)
      - Heinz, Susanna Wilder
        - Autobiography, [1987] (Box 17, Folder 298)
        - Biographical information, 1965-82 (Box 17, Folder 299)
        - Smith College: 25th reunion, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 300)
        - Transcripts, 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 301)
      - Samter family: notes, [1987] (Box 17, Folder 302)
      - Wilder & Buell
        - Behman, Marguerite, Lindenwood Tales, 1921 (Box 17, Folder 303)
      - Wilder, Herbert Merrill
        - Correspondence about, 1986-87 (Box 17, Folder 304)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS
      - Heinz, Bernard, 1915-
        - Album, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 305)
  - December 1993 Acquisition, 1917–1993; 0.21 linear feet (1 half box)
    The December 1993 Acquisition consists of one box. The series includes family writings, personal memorabilia, and photographs.
    Arrangement
    The December 1993 Acquisition is arranged in loose groupings as it was received by the library.
    - Writings and research
      - "Memories of My Childhood" written by Rosa Abueles, 1989–1993 (Box 19, Folder 319)
    - Photographs
      - Photographs of Mrs. Virginia Thurman Coke, Mrs. Augustus W. Durkee, Joseph Loving, and Mary Noble Loving, undated (Box 19, Folder 320)
    - Personal Memorabilia
      - World War (I) medals and pin, 1917–1919 (Box 19, Folder 321)
  - December 1994 Acquisition, 1898–1992; 12.63 linear feet (16 boxes)
    The December 1994 Acquisition is arranged in loose groupings as it was received by the library.
    The December 1994 Acquisition contains Bernard Heinz's wrting and research both from his personal projects and assignments for newspapers and magazines. Also included are family photographs from his side of the family and Susanna Wilder's side of the family. The series also includes his personal papers.
    - Bernard Heinz's Writings and Research
      - Articles in The New Haven Register
        - "Treasure Trove of Old Bricks Uncovered on Campus at Yale", The New Haven Register, original newspaper and copies. Also copies of the Yale Daily News article "Yale diggers discovered yellowed 'Brick Road'"., 1974 August 5 (Box 20, Folder 322)
        - "From The Old Library to Dwight Hall A Yale Building's 130 Years of History and Nostalgia" original newspaper and copies, 1974 September 8 (Box 20, Folder 323)
        - "Metheglin was Used for Special Celebrations 200 Years Ago", original newspaper and copies, 1977 February 28 (Box 20, Folder 324)
        - "City's 1837 Economy Stymied Italian Colony", copy and original newspaper, 1977 June 12 (Box 20, Folder 325)
        - "The Dead Shall be Raised", copies and original newspaper, 1978 March 8 (Box 20, Folder 326)
        - "Boot-Scraper Theology", copies, notes and original newspaper, 1978 March 16 (Box 20, Folder 327)
        - "New Haven's Green- A Dedication", The New Haven Register, multiple newspaper copies, 1978 May 22 (Box 20, Folder 328)
        - "Hillhouse Avenue", The New Haven Register, original newspaper, 1978 March 29 (Box 20, Folder 329)
        - "Adams Poem Marks Rare Discovery", clippings and copies, 1978 July 16 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 436)
        - "Collection at Yale Yields Treasures", clippings and copies, 1978 August 20 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 437)
        - "Street Signs- Canal and Lock", American Canals and The New Haven Register, original newspaper and copies, 1979 May; 1978 June 9 (Box 20, Folder 330)
        - "They're Big Time in Miniature Art", original newspaper and correspondence with Clifford T. Chieffo, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 331)
        - "American Furniture Her Forte", original newspaper and copies, 1978 September 3 (Box 20, Folder 332)
        - "Theodore Winthrop- Civil War Hero and Secret Author", original newspaper, 1978 September 24 (Box 20, Folder 333)
        - "Historical Director Eager for Public to View Exhibits", original newspaper and letter from Floyd Shumay to Bernard Heinz, 1978 October 8 (Box 20, Folder 334)
        - "Webster's Dictionary Published 150 Years Ago", original newspaper and copies, 1978 November 12 (Box 20, Folder 335)
        - "200-Year- Old Battle of City Schedule for Re-Enactment", multiple copies of original newspaper, 1979 March 4 (Box 20, Folder 336)
        - "The Placid Stone", multiple copies of original newspaper, 1979 March 14 (Box 20, Folder 337)
        - "First Japanese Student Remembered: Century- Old Friendship Celebrated at Yale", original newspaper and copies, 1979 March 16 (Box 20, Folder 338)
        - "Silliman Toiled Here", original newspaper and copies, 1979 March 23 (Box 20, Folder 339)
        - "In Sight: Yale", original newspaper and copies, 1979 March 29 (Box 20, Folder 340)
        - "Signature's Message", original newspaper, 1979 April 5 (Box 20, Folder 341)
        - "Morocco: A 'Different' Country but One Well Worth Knowing", clippings and copies, 1979 April 22 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 438)
        - "U.S. Scientists Seek to Authenticate Holy Shroud", original newspaper, 1979 June 10 (Box 20, Folder 342)
        - "'Lost' Painting May Bring Record Bids", original newspaper, 1979 October 21 (Box 20, Folder 343)
        - "New Haveners Feel at Home in New York's Cooperstown", original newspaper, 1979 November 11 (Box 20, Folder 344)
        - "Early Connecticut: Up from Puritanism", original newspaper, 1980 March 16 (Box 20, Folder 345)
        - "How Yale became the center for Early American Art", original newspaper, 1980 April 27 (Box 20, Folder 346)
        - "Hill towns of north Italy preserve glories of past", clippings and copies, 1980 November 23 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 439)
        - "Boston 'Brahims': Origin of a specie", clippings and copies, 1981 January 18 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 442)
        - "The Essence of Color", clippings, 1981 July 5 (Box 20, Folder 347)
        - "A Reappraisal of Rodin" written by Lou Spitalnick, 1981 August 23 (Box 20, Folder 348)
        - "Falkland crisis evidence of British ability to close ranks", clipping and correspondence, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 349)
        - "World has much to learn from war in the Falklands", clippings, 1982 June 25 (Box 20, Folder 350)
        - "Observer favors British style of getting information", clippings, 1982 September 10 (Box 21, Folder 351)
        - "Yankee salt box tales", clipping, 1982 October 10 (Box 21, Folder 352)
        - "Boom or bust? The Parallels of '29 and now are scary", clipping, 1982 October 27 (Box 21, Folder 353)
        - "Bountiful Farmington", clippings, 1983 January 30 (Box 21, Folder 354)
        - "Dickinson held a mirror up to elite of state", clippings, 1983 October 2 (Box 21, Folder 355)
        - "Cole, Wadsworth: Their friendship enriched the state", original newspaper and copies, 1983 December 18 (Box 21, Folder 356)
        - "New Haven 350" issue (2 copies), 1988 April 24 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 440-441)
      - Articles in Yale Alumni Magazine
        - "The First Black Student" clippings and magazine, 1978 November (Box 21, Folder 357)
        - "Silliman the Cosmopolitan", magazine and clippings, 1980 February (Box 21, Folder 358)
        - "Hillhouse Avenue: a museum of the New Haven of long ago", magazines and photocopies, 1982 June (Box 21, Folder 359)
        - "A Yale man's painting brings in a fortune", magazines, 1982 October (Box 21, Folder 360)
        - "Old Yale: the obscure virtues of Street Hall", 1983 November (Box 21, Folder 361)
        - Copies of letters to the editor and full magazine, 1985 May (Box 21, Folder 362)
        - "Landmarks: Grove Street Cemetery", magazines and photocopies, 1986 June (Box 21, Folder 363)
        - "Old Yale: New Haven's oldest building was a big undertaking for Yale", three copies, 1986 November (Box 21, Folder 364)
      - Articles in The Hartford Courant
        - "Frederic E. Church's Opulent Homestead", clippings and copies, 1980 May 18 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 443)
        - "Touring New Haven Green", clippings and copies, 1980 August 10 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 444)
        - "A Place for Dying", clippings and copies, 1981 April 12 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 445)
        - "Save the Fair Haven Sharpie", two magazines, 1981 June 7 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 446)
        - "Revived Providence Has New Magnetic Appeal for Visitors", The Hartford Courant, original newspaper, 1981 August 9 (Box 21, Folder 365)
        - "England's Secret Puritan Chapels", clippings and photocopies, 1981 December 20 (Box 21, Folder 366)
        - "New Haven's Refugee Dixwell Had Roots Deep in Dover", The Hartford Courant, copies and newpapers, 1983 March 13 (Box 21, Folder 367)
      - Articles in The New York Times
        - "A Homespun View of the Revolution", original newspaper, 1977 May 1 (Box 21, Folder 368)
        - "Vivid Reminders of Brooklyn Past", copy and original newspaper, 1977 September 4 (Box 21, Folder 369)
        - "Hallowed Ground in New Haven", The New York Times, clippings and copies, 1977 December 18 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 447)
        - "Touring Neo- Gothic New York" by Barbara Crossette, The New York Times, 1978 February 3 (Box 22, Folder 370)
        - "Hunting Treasure in the Streets", The New York Times, copy and original newspaper, 1978 March 5 (Box 22, Folder 371)
      - Articles in Unitarian Universalist World
        - "How the Puritans worshipped: What is a caudle cup?", Unitarian Universalist World, clippings, 1977 January 15 (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 448)
        - "British chapel presents an unusual face", copy and original newspaper, 1978 February 1 (Box 22, Folder 372)
        - "First selectman is first woman, first UU", copies and original newspaper, 1978 June 15 (Box 22, Folder 373)
        - "'Channing Year' project may produce new answers", original newspaper, 1980 April 1 (Box 22, Folder 374)
        - "Time to reexamine the claim of Jefferson's Unitarianism?", original newspaper, 1980 May 1 (Box 22, Folder 375)
      - "The Farmington Canal", Connecticut, copies and original magazine, 1979 December (Box 22, Folder 376)
      - "Polar Expedition", Health Affairs Magazine from the University of Pennsylvania, magazines, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 377)
      - Nathaniel Jocelyn paintings articles, 1981- (Box 27 (oversize), Folder 449)
        Articles from the New York Times and the New Haven Register on Nathaniel Jocelyn's works.
      - Banner notebook containing "Emma's Journey", undated (Box 22, Folder 378)
      - Composition notebook containing "Chapter I", undated (Box 22, Folder 379)
      - Composition notebook containing "Chapter II", undated (Box 22, Folder 380)
      - Composition notebook containing "Chapter IV", undated (Box 22, Folder 381)
      - Composition notebook without a title, undated (Box 22, Folder 382)